Rob Quinn

3919 Patterson Ave. Richmond, VA 23221 rob.m.quinn@qmail.com, 804 873 1017

SUMMARY

Blends academic training in communication and business administration with hands-on experience in agile development, QA testing, process improvement and Long Term Care claims to offer employers a track record of delivering on tasks accurately and efficiently. Known for providing best-in-class customer service and communication in a variety of business settings.

EXPERIENCE

Genworth Financial, QA Test Analyst, QA Lead for LTC Pega Eligibility Workflow and CSR Desktop Projects 01/2018 – Present

- Oversee onshore and offshore QA resources
- Review all test cases written by team members prior to execution
- Determine scope and approach for regression automation test bed
- Write and execute automated scripts using HP UFT and Selenium to create test data, as well as, for regression testing
- Partner with COE to execute Performance Testing
 - Create test operators in Calypso using SQL scripts and in Pega using update activities in Designer Studio
 - Create and update test data using SQL scripts in Calypso
 - Provide SQL scripts to performance team to execute in Oracle upon completion to verify performance scripts iterations completion
- Create User Acceptance Testing (UAT) documentation for releases and coordinate UAT
- Create production release calendar and timeline for development team
- Create and execute functional test cases
- Collaborate in Agile environment to create and groom user stories for both Eligibility and CSR projects
- Write and execute select, insert, update, and delete SQL statements to create and modify test data using Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio and Oracle SQL Developer
- Use Pega Live UI and Designer Studio to review new rules and design to come up with test strategy for new features
- Review Pega Clipboard as part of test case verification
- Work in Pega Designer Studio to modify rules in my private edit to execute different test scenario
 - o Add local actions to rules to test SLA and Get Most Urgent

Genworth Financial, QA Test Analyst, Co QA Lead for LTC Pega Eligibility Workflow Project 09/2016 – 01/2018

- Co QA lead on claims system re-platform from legacy .NET system to Pega
- Collaborated in Agile environment to create and groom user stories
- Participated in meeting with business leaders to brainstorm process improvements and Pega implementation ideas
- Demoed new features to stakeholders at sprint review meetings
- Created and executed functional test cases
- Partnered with the training team to create Pega training material
- Created UAT documentation for releases and coordinated UAT prior to release and during production checkouts
- Wrote and executed automated scripts using HP UFT and Selenium to create test data, as well as, for regression testing
- Determined scope and approach for regression automation test bed
- Wrote the Test Strategy document for the Pega LTC project and presented it to the core team, who signed off on it
- Demoed completed user stories to Product Owner for approval

Genworth Financial, QA Test Analyst, Run the Shop Team 11/2014 - 09/2016

- Managed off-shore QA resources for Run the Shop releases with a focus on process improvement
- Partnered with business leaders as part of a claims simplification process of the Initial and Ongoing Eligibility processes; pitched an idea to two directors to solve a last-minute issue, which was successfully implemented
- Responsible for running a weekly meeting with Business Analysts, Developers, and QA to troubleshoot issues and determine the scope of each month's letter release
- Worked on a 3-person team which redesigned and implemented a new UAT process
- Took part in BA, QA, and Development estimation sessions for small funded projects
- Was the owner of a project to develop an automated regression bed for all letters and forms; was
 responsible for determining scope, creating the backlog of letters to be automated, and timelines for
 development
- Worked with one developer to create a detailed document that provided an overview of the entire Calypso letter process
- Owner of the 1099 testing process
- Prepared test summary documentation which was sent out to leaders at the conclusion of testing each release to communicate testing status and any known issues
- Created release notes to be sent to the business describing any letter changes being implemented in an upcoming release
- Participated in Go No Go calls with claims leaders after production checkouts to discuss any issues discovered and options for mitigating risk

Genworth Financial, Benefit Analyst/Sr. Claim Examiner, 11/2011 - 11/2014

- Determined claim eligibility based on the claimant's contract and other data provided at time of claim, as well as, determining the need for additional information to properly determine risk
- Effectively managed and prioritized a work queue and multiple job responsibilities in a fast-paced environment
- Responsible for incoming and outgoing calls to claimants, Power of Attorneys, facilities, and other persons or entities involved in the adjudication of a claim
- Managed, tracked, and processed the department's SIU claims through collaboration with members of the SIU team in other departments

Mondial Assistance, Sr. Claims Examiner, 05/2011 – 11/2011

- Responsible for handling escalated phone calls when a customer requested a supervisor
- Worked as a Collision Damage Waiver (CDW) claim examiner; on behalf of customers, negotiated settlements with agencies such as Hertz, Avis, Budget, Enterprise etc.
- Developed training materials and conducted CDW training sessions for new hire training classes

Mondial Assistance, Claims Examiner, 08/2008 - 05/2011

- Worked with management in the Claim's department and Administration department to institute a claim "Fast Tracking" system
- Chosen as a member of the New Hire Mentoring Team

EDUCATION

University of Richmond - May 2007

B.A. Rhetoric and Communication Studies, Minor: Business Administration

Related course work: Business Statistics, Quantitative Analysis, Interpersonal Communication, Business Communication, Group Communication, Operational Management, Organizational Behavior

Certifications

- International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB) Certified Tester Foundation Level (CTFL)
- AHIP Long-Term Care Professional Designation
- Mini MBA, Robins School of Business at University of Richmond
- Certified Structured Board Interviewer and Behavior Analyst, Nowlin Associates

Proficiencies

Pega Designer Studio, SQL Server, Oracle SQL Developer, VersionOne, HP ALM, HP UFT, Selenium, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook, Excel